<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Nate Bird</title>
    <description>Follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://micro.blog/nate&quot;&gt;@nate on Micro.blog&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
    <link>https://nate.micro.blog/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 12:58:10 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 12:58:10 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>GDPR Training</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After posting about the privacy focused Overcast update I received a company training on GDPR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some interesting things I got out of it:
1) Breach Notification - regulators are to be notified within 72 hours and users should be notified “without undue delay”. 
2) Right of Access - After receiving a written request from an individual, companies are required to provide the personal data, in electronic format, free of charge, within a month.
3) Right to be Forgotten - Individuals can request that companies controlling and processing personal data erase the data and stop any further circulation of the data.
4) Data Portability - Individuals can request that their data by freely transferred to another organization.
5) Right to Object - Users have the right to object to their personal data being used for “profiling”, which is any form of automated processing to evaluate personal aspects of an individual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a user I love each one of these individual rights. From a company perspective (not the company for whom I work, I don’t speak for them.) I think it’s going to require a lot of changes to processes to be compliant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I were creating a new business I would design the business to be privacy first and avoid any and all personal data as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 12:58:09 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2018/05/01/gdpr-training.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2018/05/01/gdpr-training.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Overcast 4.2</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Marco Arment released a new version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://marco.org/2018/04/27/overcast42&quot;&gt;Overcast&lt;/a&gt; last Friday and I’m impressed with the level of privacy that is possible while still maintaining functionality and a good user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost all accounts are now anonymous - meaning that they contain NO user identifiable information. The account that is created doesn’t have a username/email or password. It uses iCloud to get a login token and uses that token to identify and login the account across devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app has the same functionality and the experience is better using login tokens than having to remember yet another account name and password and logging in and setting up 2FA. All of that nonsense just disappears. It’s better for the user because Overcast can’t track the individual. It’s better for Marco because he doesn’t have to manage personal information because their isn’t any to manage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to seeing this shift in application design - privacy first design. Designing an application to have privacy first requires a lot of foresight and planning. It is much more difficult to add/remove personal information because it requires changing so many workflows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I applaud Marco and other developers who are pushing privacy first application design.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 08:53:51 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2018/05/01/overcast.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2018/05/01/overcast.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A new trailer for Solo: A Star Wars Story! I’m pretty excited about this. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jPEYpryMp2s&quot;&gt;www.youtube.com/watch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 11:39:03 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2018/04/09/a-new-trailer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2018/04/09/a-new-trailer.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Make a Dent in the Universe</title>
        
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To do great work, you need to feel that you’re making a difference. That you’re putting a meaningful dent in the universe. That you’re part of something important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The older I become the more important it is to me that I’m doing meaningful work. When I was just starting out in programming I just wanted to be doing anything - learn new things or participate in some way. Now, I’m a little more deliberate with my time (because I, seemingly, have less free time). I’m also more choosy with what projects I participate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not in a position in life where I’m comfortable starting my own side venture and going it on my own. That time has passed as my priorities have changed but I still have side projects and my main job does have a meaningful impact on people’s lives and health. People live longer and have improved quality of life because of software I’ve written. That gets me through long meetings and onerous documentation requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I realize that my children and grandchildren are my legacy, and collectively, they will put a bigger dent in the universe than I can by myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: This is part of a series of posts inspired by re-reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://basecamp.com/books/rework&quot;&gt;Rework&lt;/a&gt;, by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dhh&quot;&gt;DHH&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jasonfried&quot;&gt;Jason Fried&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 10:53:51 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2018/03/14/make-a-dent.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2018/03/14/make-a-dent.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Be a Starter</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2008 I created my own business. I registered an LLC and tried to create a web application that could host simple web sites for carpet cleaners. While it didn’t work out how I envisioned I fancied calling myself an entrepreneur. I was building something new. I was going to put carpet cleaners on the internet. I did those things, only on a much smaller scale than I initially envisioned. But I did get the ‘create’ something bug. I learned that I liked creating things. New apps, new workflows, new processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While entrepreneur is a loaded word anyone can be a starter. You can start something within the company where you work. You can start your own thing selling stuff online. It may not be to the grand scale you initially imagine but you’ll feel good doing what you love and you’ll learn a lot along the way. Do it. Be a starter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: This is part of a series of posts inspired by re-reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://basecamp.com/books/rework&quot;&gt;Rework&lt;/a&gt;, by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dhh&quot;&gt;DHH&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jasonfried&quot;&gt;Jason Fried&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 13:47:33 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2018/03/13/be-a-starter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2018/03/13/be-a-starter.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Workaholism</title>
        
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s considered a badge of honor to kill yourself over a project.
I’ve been in this position a few times in my career. One particular time came just after Thanksgiving one year. We were creating an application and were told we had to have it done by the end of the year. We were six months into the project and I felt we were about half done. It was an impossible task for our small team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We contracted help but it took until the end of the year to just get them up to speed and on board. I was managing the project and assigning tasks and drawing up interfaces and writing requirements for the contractors as we went. We, of course, missed the end of year deadline and didn’t wrap things up until mid February (which is still a miracle in my opinion).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lesson I learned during that time was that it wasn’t worth it. I felt guilty for not working during the two days I took off for Christmas. I missed my brother’s wedding at the beginning of January because the contractors were coming on and needed guidance of what to do and I was the only one who could do that. There were reasons for why I worked 18 hours a day for 10-12 weeks. There are always reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end it didn’t really matter. The fact that we finished in February didn’t matter. We could have finished a month later and it would have turned out fine. I could have worked regular hours, hired the same contractors, finished in March, attended by brother’s wedding, spent time with my kids during the Christmas holidays, and not suffered burnout for the three months after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now when I receive a deadline from on high I push back because long term workaholism isn’t worth it. It usually isn’t even necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: This is part of a series of posts inspired by re-reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://basecamp.com/books/rework&quot;&gt;Rework&lt;/a&gt;, by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dhh&quot;&gt;DHH&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jasonfried&quot;&gt;Jason Fried&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 13:37:02 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2018/03/11/workaholism.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2018/03/11/workaholism.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Why Grow?</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The premise of this section is that businesses are judged based on their size and that bigger is better and more successful. DHH and JF refute this notion and propose that any business has an optimal size and that may be just one person or 5,000 people. You need to find the right size for your business and go with it. It may change over time. Just let it happen organically. The highest priority shouldn’t be to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work in a very large company. Multiple international sites all over the world big. But my team has two members. And for now that is enough. I would like a third member for a couple reasons. First, to alleviate some of the pressure we have to deliver on the schedule we’ve set. Second, to bring more diversity and perspective to the team. Third, we need more leverage within our business group and size actually matters for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is the balance I find myself faced with. We are a very productive team. We ship software often (compared to other teams in the company). We write good code. We are super efficient. Our software doesn’t have many issues. But those are also problems in a large company. We don’t receive the visibility of other teams because no one is talking about us. When nothing goes wrong then no one cares. Management cares when there are problems to solve. If you don’t have problems then you don’t receive attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: This is part of a series of posts inspired by re-reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://basecamp.com/books/rework&quot;&gt;Rework&lt;/a&gt;, by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dhh&quot;&gt;DHH&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jasonfried&quot;&gt;Jason Fried&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 16:38:16 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2018/03/10/why-grow.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2018/03/10/why-grow.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Planning is guessing</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The process we follow for releasing software starts with a design planning meeting. It has a form to plan the release and a full grant chart is supposed to be attached to the document. All of this happens before any code is written. The end date is chosen before we get a chance to dig into the details. The schedule always needs to be adjusted. The plain never stays the same. And it always is late. The dates are chosen so far in advance with an optimistic mindset that it is nearly impossible to keep them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planning is useful when you need to coordinate with other groups. But only a couple weeks in advance. I don’t know how many times a deploy has been scheduled a month or so in advance and that date is never hit. But we can plan what needs to be done and then work on the highest priority items until we finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I like to plan what needs to be done but things go awry when you schedule them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: This is a series of posts inspired by re-reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://basecamp.com/books/rework&quot;&gt;Rework&lt;/a&gt;, by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dhh&quot;&gt;DHH&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jasonfried&quot;&gt;Jason Fried&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 21:33:34 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2018/03/06/planning-is-guessing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2018/03/07/planning-is-guessing.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Failure is not a rite of passage</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Failure is not a prerequisite for success.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the corporate world failure isn’t celebrated like in startup culture. In fact I would say the pendulum has swung the other way and everything is protected so much and all risk is analyzed, categorized, and catalogued. Not allowing failure in the process means that a lot of extra work is done before anything is released. It also means that small mistakes can take a long time to fix because of the long time frames required to release something new because the new thing can’t have any known issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So while failure in startup culture is celebrated and the motto is move fast and break things. The corporate world is moving so slowly that problems compound and reaction to changes takes months or years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A healthy balance of fast processes with careful consideration and thought into what is released goes a long way to creating quality products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: This is a series of posts inspired by re-reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://basecamp.com/books/rework&quot;&gt;Rework&lt;/a&gt;, by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dhh&quot;&gt;DHH&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jasonfried&quot;&gt;Jason Fried&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 21:32:47 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2018/03/06/failure-is-not.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2018/03/07/failure-is-not.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Ignore the real world</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The real world says, “the only things that win are what people already know and do, even if those things are flawed and inefficient.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the corporate world the things people know and do are usually processes that are strictly defined or mandated from above without reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, the use of MS Word for all documentation or getting signatures from all departments (regardless of whether it effects them) to deploy code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my team, I’m moving our documents to a git repo and writing them in markdown to avoid hours of formatting templates and reviewing redlines in Word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a small change but it will have a big impact on our ability to release quickly. The process managers might balk at this change but it will be much easier to maintain and my team will continue to deliver results with much less resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: This is a series of posts inspired by re-reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://basecamp.com/books/rework&quot;&gt;Rework&lt;/a&gt;, by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dhh&quot;&gt;DHH&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jasonfried&quot;&gt;Jason Fried&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 16:34:08 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2018/03/04/ignore-the-real.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2018/03/04/ignore-the-real.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Fixing the Apple TV Remote</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Apple TV Remote receives a lot of criticism about its ergonomics and usability. Well, Elgato has a nice cover for the Remote that has solved some of the ergonomics issues, at least for me. I can now always feel which end is top and bottom by feel (the cord). It is grippy so it stays on the couch arm without worry of sliding off. It’s also a bit bigger so it fits better in my hand and doesn’t get lost in the cushions as easily. As a bonus, it’s magnetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://nate.micro.blog/uploads/2018/a8214a5393.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;599&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://nate.micro.blog/uploads/2018/8d9f3df500.jpg&quot; width=&quot;599&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://nate.micro.blog/uploads/2018/b29a3b0f96.jpg&quot; width=&quot;599&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 11:03:35 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2018/02/23/fixing-the-apple.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2018/02/23/fixing-the-apple.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My day ended like this. How was yours?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://nate.micro.blog/uploads/2018/4b612acebd.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 19:22:16 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2018/02/10/my-day-ended.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2018/02/11/my-day-ended.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Podcast: The Compass - My Perfect Country</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The linked episode is part of a series about building a perfect country. They visit countries all over the world and find something in which that particular country excels. Rwanda has amazing gender equality laws and regulations. It’s a great podcast outside of my normal tech episodes. &lt;a href=&quot;https://overcast.fm/+Ip9RuwDkg&quot;&gt;overcast.fm/+Ip9RuwDk…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 08:05:10 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2018/02/08/podcast-the-compass.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2018/02/08/podcast-the-compass.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Latest Star Wars LEGO project - Poe Dameron’s Resistance X-Wing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://nate.micro.blog/uploads/2018/491a83b90c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;599&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 13:33:34 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2018/02/03/latest-star-wars.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2018/02/03/latest-star-wars.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The girls and I built my (yes, I get LEGO for Christmas) Kylo Ren’s Command Shuttle over Christmas break and re-built my daughter’s Millenium Falcon from scratch (finding each piece among the bins of LEGO!!!) this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This seems like a precursor of episode IX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://nate.micro.blog/uploads/2018/da074f30eb.jpg&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 10:18:13 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2018/01/15/the-girls-and.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2018/01/15/the-girls-and.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the benefits of having kids who like Star Wars and robots is having these two for company on my desk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fun fact: sometimes they wake up and move around and start chatting. It’s startled me a more than once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://nate.micro.blog/uploads/2018/1d394255ee.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;458&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 10:14:21 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2018/01/04/one-of-the.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2018/01/04/one-of-the.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>iPhone X Tips</title>
        
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;general-iphone-x-tips&quot;&gt;General iPhone X Tips&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) Fast(er) access to the multi-tasking switcher. Pull up from the bottom less than an inch, hesitate, then lift your finger from the screen. It is “pull up and lift finger” rather than a “flicking upward” gesture. Also, you don’t need to wait for the haptic feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) You can still Force quit apps in the multitasker. First enter the multi-tasking view, then hold down on any of the apps. A red circle will appear in the top left of each app screen. You can tap the red circle or swipe up on the app screen to force quit each app. I don’t recommend force quitting any apps regularly. This should only be used in situations where you believe a particular app is misbehaving (i.e. Facebook). Force quitting all apps does not improve battery life. In fact, it reduces battery life by requiring more processing to start rather than resuming apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Animoji doesn’t work in the dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) You can take a screenshot by pushing either volume button and the power button at the same time. Editing or sharing screenshots is awesome in iOS 11. Try it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) If you hold down the top volume button and the power button at the same time for 2-3 seconds it will lock the phone and disable all biometric authentication (Face ID and Touch ID). Some call this the Police hold because you can activate it while handing your phone to an officer. Once activated only the passcode can unlock the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;face-id-tips&quot;&gt;Face ID Tips&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) Works in bright light or darkness just as well as indoor lighting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Requires being right side up to work; It doesn’t work sideways or upside down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) It needs to be 8” - 24” from your face to work consistently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) The best way to use Face ID is to pretend that your phone doesn’t have a passcode or Touch ID. Just tap the screen to wake the phone and then swipe up to go to the home screen or the previously used app.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 10:11:41 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2018/01/03/iphone-x-tips.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2018/01/03/iphone-x-tips.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Yearly Security Audit</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Around this time of year I start auditing some of my online security. Here are some links and tips so you can do the same. Have a happy and safe 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I clean out all the connected applications to Facebook, Twitter, and Google. Usually these are services I don’t use (or don’t exist anymore). They generally have more access to my data than I’m comfortable. Clean it up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Facebook - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/settings&quot;&gt;www.facebook.com/settings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Twitter - &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/settings/applications&quot;&gt;twitter.com/settings/…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Google - &lt;a href=&quot;https://myaccount.google.com/u/0/permissions&quot;&gt;myaccount.google.com/u/0/permi…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://1password.com&quot;&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt; to manage all of my passwords. They have a handy section for security audit. You can check how old your passwords are but I mainly focus on the &lt;em&gt;Watchtower&lt;/em&gt;  and &lt;em&gt;Weak Passwords&lt;/em&gt; sections.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 15:55:34 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2018/01/02/yearly-security-audit.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2018/01/02/yearly-security-audit.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ready for Christmas morning!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://nate.micro.blog/uploads/2017/bbd3ba3464.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;599&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 00:04:12 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2017/12/25/ready-for-christmas.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2017/12/25/ready-for-christmas.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I started swimming again today. My left arm has been hurting when I raise it above my head for the last month or so - probably from playing tennis. The first 1000 yards really hurt but my arm is much better now. Kind of a physical therapy…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 16:04:44 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2017/11/06/i-started-swimming.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2017/11/06/i-started-swimming.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure I’ll use micro blog enough to pay for it. It’s cool but I don’t post enough to make it worth paying. It’s not you; it’s me. 🙃&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 23:52:54 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2017/11/04/im-not-sure.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2017/11/05/im-not-sure.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Interesting that Face ID works in the dark but Animoji needs light. #iPhoneX&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 23:50:43 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2017/11/04/interesting-that-face.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2017/11/05/interesting-that-face.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An after midnight post for the badge. 😜&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:13:56 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2017/11/04/an-after-midnight.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2017/11/04/an-after-midnight.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;iPhone X is in hand and it’s awesome!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 18:46:03 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2017/11/03/iphone-x-is.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2017/11/03/iphone-x-is.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One more day! #iPhoneX&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 15:54:23 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2017/11/02/one-more-day.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2017/11/02/one-more-day.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m getting excited about my new iPhone coming. My first new iPhone since the 6. The reviews today are only increasing the excitement. Yay!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 15:26:21 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2017/10/31/im-getting-excited.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2017/10/31/im-getting-excited.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I had a great time visiting my mom this weekend and enjoying the beautiful fall colors of Wenatchee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://nate.micro.blog/uploads/2017/208909d23c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;599&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 08:59:52 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2017/10/29/i-had-a.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2017/10/29/i-had-a.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I visited my dad’s grave today. Even after three years I still miss him a lot. He was a good man. I hope I can live up to his legacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://nate.micro.blog/uploads/2017/2a5de67811.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://nate.micro.blog/uploads/2017/f4701f178d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;599&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 02:11:22 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2017/10/28/i-visited-my.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2017/10/28/i-visited-my.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m enjoying the falls colors of Seattle this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://nate.micro.blog/uploads/2017/1624c5d90a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 16:08:55 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2017/10/26/im-enjoying-the.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2017/10/26/im-enjoying-the.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Finished the third day of Thinking in Swift in Seattle. This intermediate course has been insightful and dug into different types of ‘map’ and various ViewController communication types. I recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 19:57:20 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://nate.micro.blog/2017/10/25/finished-the-third.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://nate.micro.blog/2017/10/25/finished-the-third.html</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
